5，4，3，2，RD-180发动机点火，1
15, 4, 3, 2, we have ignition of the RD-180 main engine, 1
联合发射联盟宇宙神5火箭起飞
Liftoff of the United Launch Alliance Atlas V rocket
宇宙神5火箭的RD-180发动机点火
The Atlas V RD-180 main engine ignites
起飞推力超过860,000磅（390吨）
and generate more than 860,000 pounds of thrust
推举火箭飞离发射台
to lift the rocket from the pad
起飞后不久，火箭开始程序转弯来进入合适的飞行轨迹
Shortly after liftoff, Atlas begins pitch over to attain proper flight path
同时减小火箭飞行时承受的压力
while minimizing the pressure the vehicle experiences during flight
宇宙神5火箭在1分17秒达到1马赫，即1倍音速
The Atlas V reaches Mach 1, the speed of sound, at 1 minute 17 seconds
4分4秒，起飞级燃料耗尽，其主发动机关机
At 4 minutes 4 seconds, propellent level deplete, and main engine shuts down
6秒后，宇宙神-半人马上面级分离系统启动，从而与起飞级分离
6 seconds later, the Atlas Centaur separation system activates to release the booster stage
此时火箭重量只剩起飞时的7%多一点
The vehicle weighs a little more than 7% of what it did at liftoff
4分20秒，半人马上面级发动机第一次点火
At 4 minutes 20 seconds, the first Centaur main engine burn begins
从而把半人马火箭送入圆形轨道
sending the Centaur into a circular orbit
在整流罩分离前
Approaching payload fairing jettison
半人马火箭每秒燃烧51磅（23.1千克）燃料
the Centaur is burning propellant at a rate of 51lb/s
速度超过每小时10,000英里（16000千米/小时，4444米/秒）
traveling at more than 10,000 miles per hour
高度79英里（127千米），水平飞行距离252英里（406千米）
and located 79 miles in altitude and 252 miles downrange
起飞过程中，直径4米的整流罩将保护洞察号
During ascent, InSight is protected inside a 4m diameter payload fairing
约4分28秒，整流罩分离
At approximately 4 minutes 28 seconds, the payload fairing is jettisoned
13分16秒
At 13 minutes 16 seconds
半人马火箭主发动机第一次关机（MECO-1）
cutoff of the Centaur main engine, or MECO-1 occurs
任务进入一小时滑行阶段
The mission now enter an-hour-long coast phase
在快到1小时15分时
At nearly 1 hour and 15 minutes
半人马火箭发动机重启，进行第二次，也是最后一次点火
the Centaur main engine is restarted for the second and final burn
将半人马火箭送入星箭分离前的路径
placing Centaur on its path to spacecraft separation
大约4分49秒后
Approximately 4 minutes and 49 seconds later
半人马火箭主发动机最后一次关机
final cutoff of the Centaur main engine occurs
1小时28分40秒
At 1 hour 28 minutes and 40 seconds
NASA的洞察号与半人马火箭探测器分离，进入前往火星的旅途
Centaur releases NASA's InSight spacecraft on its journey to Mars
而火星立方星1号、2号将从位于半人马火箭底部储箱外面的立方星适配器释放
Deploying from dispensers mounted on the aft bulkhead carrier on Centaur
它们将在洞察号进入火星大气、下降、着陆阶段提供实时通讯中继
the Mars Cube One, or MarCO cube sates will provide real-time communication relay
covering the entry, descent and landing of InSight on Mars
火星立方星1号将于升空后1小时29分分离
MarCO-A separates 1 hour 29 minutes into flight
48秒后，火星立方星2号也将分离
followed 48 seconds later, by the separation of MarCO-B